

Milan Klaasman

MSc. Artificial Intelligence

3 November 1993

Amsterdam, Netherlands

+31 625 500 134

milanklaasman@gmail.com

Linked in /in/milan-klaasman

GitHub /MKlaasman

Summary —

Data Scientist, with affinity for sports, data analytics, machine learning and solving all kinds of puzzles. Focused and dedicated to become an expert in football analytics. I would describe myself as an enthusiastic, positive, assertive and trustworthy person, with great analytical and problem solving skills.

Interests ———

Programming (Python)

Data Analytics

Sports (Mostly: Football & Endurance)

Socializing

Work Experience

2020-2021 **Data Scientist at Centric**

Centric

At centric I have worked in multiple data science projects, where we, as a team, were responsible for the development of machine learning approaches. An example is an NLP approach for the municipality of Amsterdam, where we automatically categorise written objections

that are made against house prices.

2020 IT trainee Working Talent

> As a trainee at Working Talent, I participate in an intensive learning path in which I am trained as a certified IT-professional. The traineeship has a foundational component, in which among other things ITinfrastructure, modelling, cloud, security, databases, programming, Agile and Scrum are discussed. In the second part the training I fo-

cused on the specialisation track Data Analysis.

Feb - Aug 2019 Thesis: Predicting football event outcomes using supervised learning techniques. www.metrica-sports.com

> Setting up a a new database structure and workflow to analyse tracking and events data of over 350 professional football games using

machine learning techniques.

Data Acquisition Manager 2018 - 2019 www.metrica-sports.com

> At Metrica Sports, I was responsible for managing the daily processes of the Data Acquisition team and the data quality. Analysing and assuring the data quality by using among others Python and Matlab.

Teacher (Assistant) - Quality assurance programming course 2017

"Java for Software Testers"

At NLBC, I was working as a Teacher/Assistant-Teacher for 2-day

Java programming bootcamps for Software Testers.

Education

MSc. Artificial Intelligence 2016 - 2019 **VU University**

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Track: Research Variant Cognitive Science GPA: 7.5/10

Bsc. Human Movement Sciences 2012 - 2016 **VU University**

Amsterdam, Netherlands

Minor: Sport GPA: 6.7/10

Other activities

Travel to China and Nepal 2019-2020

2019+2020 Participation in 1st and 2nd DFB Hackathon (German Football As-

sociation), 5 month project

Implementing Clustering techniques to discover insights in crosses

in the game of football.

Utrecht Full Marathon (Time: 3:42) 2018

President of a fraternity within Student Association SSRA 2015 - 2016

Responsible for organizing meetings, accommodations and activities

for a group of 30 people.

Youth football trainer 2008 - 2013